我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present,
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
and now our world is more dangerous than ever,
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
这是什么
What is that?
这是我老爸以前和我玩的游戏
It's a game my dad and I used to play.
是我爸爸写的信
It's a letter from my dad.
他还活着
He's still alive.
来找我
你在我体内植入一枚超能力抑制芯片
You put a power dampening chip inside me
来夺走我的速度
to take away my speed.
这是你对我态度冷淡的原因吗
Is that why you've been so cold to me?
这是你不想待在我身边的原因吗
Why you don't want to spend any time with me?
妈妈认为她在未来有一个充分的理由
Mom thinks that she had good reason
来抑制我的超能力
to suppress my powers in the future.
我支持她的决定
I support her decisions.
上午9点58分
我们就打给她吧  巴里
Let's just call it, Barry.
她应该又不来了
She's not coming. Again.
她大概是在帮詹娜照顾小孩
She's probably just helping with Jenna
这样乔和塞西尔才有时间睡个觉
so Joe and Cecile can sleep in.
难道上两个星期每天都这样吗
Every day for the past two weeks?
他们看起来确实挺累的
They look really tired.
是真的
They do.
中城美术馆
中城美术馆跳闸报警了
Tripped alarm at Central City Art Gallery.
有人在偷莫奈的画
Someone stole a Monet.
居然敢在早上十点  胆子真大
At 10:00 a.m.? That's bold.
中城警局正在赶往  嫌疑人往西边逃跑了
CCPD's en route, suspect heading west on Ruger.
嫌疑人位置更新
窃贼刚刚从第五个路口转弯进拉米雷斯
The thief just turned on to Ramirez off of Fifth.
我就快到了
Almost there.
他身上什么都没有
He's not carrying anything.
那是因为他刚把画交给了另一个人
Because he handed it off to someone else.
-诺拉  -诺拉
- Nora? - Nora?
-他往哪走了  -我来对付他
- Uh, where's he headed? - I got him.
我可以拦住一个开着摩托车的人
I can stop someone on a motor cycle.
不  诺拉  让巴里来帮你  好吗
No, Nora, let Barry help, okay--
你是切断了我的通话吗  小姐
I know you did not just cut me off, miss thing.
抓到你啦
Gotcha.
你还好吗
You okay?
闪 电 侠
第五季
第五集
所以我们需要训练  诺拉  每天都要
This is why we train, Nora. Every single day.
不是你想练才练  也不是疯了才要练
Not when you feel like it, not because you're mad,
所以当你出外勤时
and why you always have someone in your ear
需要有个人跟你说话协助你
when you're in the field to help you.
-我知道  -那为什么要关掉我的信号
- I know that. - Then why did you turn me off?
因为我不想再听你的话了
Because I can't listen to you anymore.
你总是说一些居高临下的
It's always the same condescending,
"我知道的比你多"的废话
I-know-better-than-you crap.
我只是想成为我自己
I just want to be me
而你坐在桌子的后面
and you sit behind your desk
每次都跟我说"不"
and you say "No" Every time
我一辈子都在听这句话  已经受不了了
and I've been hearing it my whole life and I'm sick of it.
-你的一生  -是的  妈妈
- Your whole life? - Yes, Mom.
自从我记事以来  你一直都没变过
Since I can remember, and you never change.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
你知道吗  诺拉
You know, Nora,
我希望你可以试着理解
I wish you would try to understand
现在的妈妈
who your mom is today,
不要把她看成未来的妈妈
and stop seeing her as who she becomes in the future.
-这是给你的  -这什么东西
- That's for you. - The hell is this?
这是用来抵扣我欠的债的时间
Well, that's the hours to apply against my debt.
用于揭露超能力连环杀人犯蝉的身份
Fruitful hours spent getting closer to uncovering
所耗费的成果丰厚的时间
the identity of your serial meta-killer, Cicada.
怎么做的
And how's that?
我用了一个对你来说很复杂的公式
Well, I apply a complex formula--complex for you,
包含终极速度和尖端科研实验室
involving the terminal velocity and the weight
卫星的重量  还有巴里和诺拉
of the S.T.A.R. Labs' satellite and the velocity of Barry
时间旅行时的速度  当他们...
and Nora traveling when they--
摧毁了那个卫星  对吧  从而让我推断出
destroy the satellite, right, allowing me to conclude that...
卫星的残骸  卫星的碎片
The debris from the satellite, the satellite shrapnel,
然后那个将会变成蝉的人
and the man who would become our Cicada
刚好会在这里面被发现
would be found within this perimeter.
这用了你多长时间
And that took you how long?
哇哦  斯诺博士
Oof, Dr. Snow.
十八个小时  因为我的代数一般般
Eighteen hours 'cause I'm only semi-excellent at algebra.
你知道这是微积分  对吧
You know this is calculus, right?
各位  是这样的  微积分  代数
Guys, look, calculon, algebra,
都不能告诉我们碎片落在哪儿
either way it doesn't tell us where the shrapnel fell.
非也  你必须扫遍整座城市
Mais non. You have to scan the entire city
来找到具体的位置
to find the exact location.
好吧  所以你要用萨利卫星去找萨利卫星
Okay, so you need Sally the satellite to find Sally the satellite
然后用托马斯·斯诺去指向托马斯·斯诺
and we need Thomas Snow to point us to Thomas Snow.
- 他没跟上你  -指向托马斯·斯诺
- You lost him. - At Thomas Snow.
关于我爸的线索  我们已经到死胡同了
We've hit a dead end with regards to my father.
我从头到尾看了他所有的笔记和文章
I looked through all of his notes and papers.
已经没有可用的隐藏信息了
There's no more hidden messages we could use.
用了卫星运行DNA识别模式  但是
A satellite to run DNA recognition patterns but...
我以为十岁失去他就很难了  但是
I thought losing him when I was ten was hard, but,
问题是他还活着
the idea that he's out there
但我也许没办法找到他
and I might not be able to get to him...
也许我可以帮忙
Maybe I can help you.
你的超能力不是不能用吗
I thought your powers weren't working.
不是全部  但这个可以做到
No, not fully, but this I can do.
你没事吧
You okay?
我看到他了
I saw him.
看到你爸在一间办公室里
I saw your dad in-- in an office
在笔记本电脑上画图
sketching something in a notebook.
我看不出他画的是什么
I couldn't quite make out what it was.
还看到别的什么吗
Did you see anything else?
黑板上写了一些方程式
Um, equations on a chalkboard.
我们家里的办公室没有黑板
We didn't have a chalkboard in our home office.
不  把你所看到全都告诉我们
No, but tell us everything that you saw.
墙上和桌上有什么  他当时穿什么衣服
What's on the walls, what's on the desk, what he was wearing.
毫无遗漏地告诉我们
Leave nothing out.
他有个身份牌  一个黄色的标志
He had an ID. It was, like, a yellow logo,
像是黄色的政府建筑
like a yellow state building.
黄色标志  不是政府建筑
Yellow logo, so, not a state building.
是大学建筑
A university building.
哈德逊大学
Hudson University.
-斯泰因教授  -你认识他吗
- Professor Stein. - And did you know him?
我知道他崇拜他
I knew he admired him,
但我不知道他们是朋友
but I didn't realize that they were friends.
这下秘密越来越多了
Add that to the growing list of secrets.
我们走一趟吧
Let's go drive.
谢谢
Thank you.
应该的
It's what I do.
娜塔莉  来  在婚礼前我有个惊喜要给你
Natalie, come here. I have a pre-wedding surprise for you.
无瑕的方形钻石镶嵌在白金上
Flawless asscher cut diamond set in Platinum.
超过383克拉
Over 383 karats.
我曾祖父在结婚当日
My great grandfather gave this to his wife
把它送给了她妻子
on their wedding day.
明天  它就是你的了
Tomorrow, it's yours.
明天  太久了好难熬
Tomorrow? That's torture.
别走
Stop!
恭喜你
Mazel Tov.
你能形容一下你看到的那个人吗
Can you describe the man that you saw?
那都不能叫人  因为他走路的样子
I'd barely call him a man, the way he moved.
而且在他回头看我的时候
And when he looked back at me,
太吓人了
it was terrifying.
-你看到他的脸吗  -看不到
- Could you see his face? - No.
他戴着小丑面具
He was wearing some sort of clown mask.
你确定他只偷走了项链吗
And you're sure the necklace is the only thing that was stolen.
是的  那条项链是独一无二的
Yes, and it's irreplaceable.
谢谢你们  感激不尽
Thank you. I really appreciate it.
惊喜吧
Hey. A nice surprise.
就算在中城  百万珠宝大盗
Yeah, well, a million dollar jewelry theft is still news
也还是大新闻
even in Central City, so.
那你不去抓超能力者吗
So, you're off the metas, huh?
今天不去了
Yeah, no, not today.
我想我就继续追踪这个新闻
You know, I think I'm just gonna follow up on this
趁现在还有热度
while it's still fresh.
-今晚见  好吗  -等一下
- I'll see you tonight, okay? - Okay, wait. Hang on.
我们在查的是同一件案子
I mean, we're working on the same case.
不如把资料集中在一起  也许可以携手破案
Why don't we pool resources, maybe solve this one together.
我不知道  巴里  这有点
Yeah, I don't know, Barry, it's just...
去尖端科研实验室的路上顺便吃个大贝利汉堡
Come on, grab some Big Belly on the way to S.T.A.R. Labs.
就像约会一样
It'll be like a date.
-好  -好  走吧
- All right. - All right. Come on.
这才叫生活
This is the life.
说真的  我可以一辈子留在这
Seriously, I could stay here forever.
别担心  没有妈妈的叨叨
No worries, no schrap from mom--
等一下  那是什么意思
Wait, wait, wait, what was that?
-叨叨  -叨叨
- Schrap. - Schrap?
叨叨  妈妈总是唠叨个没完
Schrap. You know, like all the nagging that mom does.
我是说她表现得像很支持我一样
I mean, she acts like she supports me,
但是她真正想要的只是一个安静无趣的女儿
but what she really wants is a boring, quiet daughter
只想一整天待在家里
who just wants to stay inside all day
而不是出去做些
instead of go out and do anything
可能有一丁点危险的事
that might be the least bit dangerous.
诺拉  这里是韦斯特家
Nora, this is the West house.
在这里  要尊重每一位韦斯特成员
In it, every West is given respect,
尤其是你的母亲
most especially your mother.
我相信她是尽心尽力把你养大的
I am sure she raised you as best she could.
她想让我对这个世界产生恐惧
She raised me to be afraid of the world.
但我是个英雄  就像老爸一样
But I'm a hero, you know, like dad.
我们必须不停奔跑
And we have to keep moving
直到所有需要我们的人都安全了
until everyone that needs us is safe.
好
Okay.
抱歉  这个要来干什么
I'm sorry, what is this for?
在乔爷爷回家的时候
When Papa Joe comes back,
这张桌子要装好
this table is going to finally be built.
你不是想要继续奔跑
You wanted to keep moving.
-必须做吗  -没错
- Oh, do I have to? - Yes.
好吧  咱们来做个交易
All right, I'll make you a deal.
你每做一次家务
For every chore you do
我就告诉你一件乔爸爸跟我说的关于
I'll tell you one thing Papa Joe told me about your father
你爸爸那些未收录进闪电侠博物馆的趣事
that didn't make it into the precious Flash museum.
塞西尔妈妈  那博物馆里
Oh, Mama Cecile, the museum has
记录了爸爸全部的伟业
a complete record of all of Dad's accomplishments.
包括巴里回到了平行世界的过去
Including the time Barry ended up in an alternate past
碰见叫做古鲁丹的黄金巨人种族那次吗
filled with golden giants called "Grodans"?
等下  什么
Wait, what?
古鲁丹
Grodans.
完成  那么那次发生了什么
Done. So then what happened?
没完成  等着
Not done. Wait for it.
那么  为什么凯特琳有
So, why exactly does Caitlin have a key
斯坦因教授老办公室的钥匙
to Professor Stein's old office?
克莱丽莎给我的钥匙  她也不知道马丁
Clarissa gave me a key. She didn't realize that Martin
和我的父亲认识对方
and my father knew each other either.
我好奇他在这里做些什么
I wonder what he was doing in here.
或许拉蒙先生能震波下那个黑板
Well, perhaps Mr. Ramon could vibe the chalkboard
这样我们就能看到了
and we could see for ourselves.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
氢链不断融合
Hydrogen chains bonded over and over.
两个氧处在绝对零度
Two oxygen at absolute zero.
就像是制作重水
It's like it's making heavy water.
不是重水
Not heavy water.
是冰
Ice.
又是我爸留下的隐藏信息吗
Another one of my father's hidden messages?
"喀俄涅"
"Khione"?
这"喀俄涅"是什么意思
What kind of a message is "Khione"?
意思很清楚
A clear one.
至少对我来说  你看  雷蒙先生
At least to me. Look, monsieur Ramon,
你之前说你可以看到斯诺博士的
you said that earlier that you could see that Dr. Snow,
父亲正在画些什么  对吗
her father sketching something, right?
那个你稍微能看清的素描
That sketch that you could almost make out...
是不是与这个很相似
Did it look a little something like this?
老天  你是极速者吗
Good lord, are you a speedster?
速写  很普通的技能
Speed sketcher. It's a modest talent.
我父亲画了我
My father was drawing me?
不是你  是喀俄涅
Not you. Khione.
喀俄涅  希腊女神
Khione, the Greek goddess.
北风的孩子  统治着冰与雪的国度
Child of the North Wind, whose realm was ice and snow.
喀俄涅
Khione.
冰霜杀手
Killer Frost.
这意味着不管托马斯在做什么
That means that whatever Thomas was doing,
他知道有两个你
he knew that there were two of you.
并且  有可能托马斯目睹了
Also, it stands to reason that Thomas was there
冰霜杀手的诞生
at the point of creation of Killer Frost.
所以  他知道冰霜杀手的真相吗
So, he knew the truth about Killer Frost?
-他知道我究竟是谁  -没错
- He knew who I really am? - Right.
-是我吓走他的吗  -不  这不是你的错
- Did I scare him away? - No, this wasn't your fault.
我不知道他为什么离开  但肯定不是因为你
Look, I don't know why he left, but it wasn't because of you,
而我们要去证明这一点
and we're gonna prove that.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  不小心没站稳
Yeah, just lost my footing there for a second.
-你...  -你看到了什么
- What- - What did you see?
你们听说过费耶拉化工吗
You guys ever hear of Viera Chemicals?
是个在郊区的老化工实验室
Oh, it's an old chem lab out in the Barrens,
但已经关闭很久了
but it's been shut down for years.
那咱们还等什么
Well, what are we waiting for?
很高兴看到你又到外面去
You know, it's been great seeing you out there again,
做你喜爱的事
doing what you love.
是啊  有些女孩长大想当超女
Yeah, I guess some girls grow up wanting to be Supergirl.
我却总是成为...
I always wanted to be
索拉达·欧布莱恩或克里斯蒂亚娜·阿曼坡
Soledad O'Brien or Christiana Amanpour.
所以是的  能重拾梦想真不错
So yeah, it's really great to reconnect.
人类毛发无DNA匹配
真奇怪  这上说我找到的毛发
That's weird. It says the hair I found
是人类的  但找不到DNA
is human but it can't pull any DNA.
再测一次试试
Maybe run it again?
别这样  诺威克
Come on, Novick.
你想要改进哥谭的天际线
You wanna improve Gotham City's skyline,
你就要选一个
you do it with a building
能吸引所有人眼光的建筑
nobody can take their eyes off of.
也就是我的作品
That's one of mine.
你和我合作   我就给你设计个建筑
You go with me, I'll design you a building
让哈利法塔看起来像是路边小店
that makes the Burj Khalifa look like a strip mall.
建筑风格就是我的一切
Architecture means everything to me.
你跟我说说
I mean, you tell me.
外边有多少建筑师
How many other architects have won
赢得过普利策奖三次
the Pritzker Prize three times?
选得好
Good choice.
这个你从哪里拿到的
Where did you get this?
在某个大礼物盒子
By some really weird markings
底部的奇怪标志上
at the bottom of a large gift box
我可以肯定它是从里边打开的
that I'm pretty sure was opened from the inside.
好吧  从现在开始要由你来
Okay, you know you're opening all of our mail
打开我们的所有快件了  好吗
from now on, right?
西弗建筑
有人报警在西弗建筑公司有炸弹威胁
Somebody called in a bomb threat at Seaver Architects.
-发生了什么事  -那东西干的
- What happened? - That thing, it did this.
闪电侠
Flash.
那东西毁了我毕生的成果
That thing destroyed my life's work.
他缩进了空调通风口吗
So, he squeezed his way through an air conditioning vent?
他能像拉尔夫那样伸缩
Yeah, he could stretch kinda like Ralph,
不同的是他戴着一副
except he was wearing a--
-小丑面具  -没错
- Clown mask. - Yup.
跟偷了韦恩豪斯家项链的人一样
Just like the guy that stole the Winehouse necklace.
这是个伸缩小丑超能力者
Mm-hmm. We got a stretching clown meta.
真是一点也不瘆人
Yeah, that's not creepy at all.
是啊
Yeah.
你又找到那种奇怪的纤维了吗
Did you find any more of those weird lines?
没有  即便还有也被埋在成堆碎石下
No, and if there's more, they're buried underneath
和那个超能力者一样
tons of rubble, just like our meta,
除非他已经从碎石里钻出来了
unless he was able to stretch out of that one too.
我肯定他已经钻出来了
Which...I'm sure he was.
-那些纤维  -怎么了
- The lines. - What?
这个超能力者能伸缩变形  对吧
Well, I mean, our meta can stretch and contort, right?
说不定他的指纹也会伸缩变形
What if his fingerprints can too?
找到匹配
彼得·梅克尔
找到了  彼得·梅克尔
Got him. Peter Merkel.
两年前因为私闯民宅被逮捕
And he was arrested for B&E two years ago.
等等  彼得·梅克尔
Wait, Peter Merkel,
亿万富翁特丽萨·梅克尔的儿子
the son of Billionaire Theresa Merkel?
资本大亨举办慈善晚宴
没错
Yup.
他是为何会从上流显贵
How does someone go from being a member of high society
沦为偷盗传家宝和轰炸建筑的人
to stealing heirlooms and blowing up buildings?
也许我们该去参加她举办的这个晚宴
Maybe we should attend this gala she's hosting
直接问她
and ask her ourselves.
要是梅克尔也在怎么办
Uh, I don't know, what if Merkel's there?
那又怎么样  我们有备而来
So what? We'll come prepared.
我带着超能力者手铐
Some meta handcuffs for me,
你带着电击枪  然后我们盛装出席
a taser for you, and we get to dress up.
-巴里  -怎么
- Barry. - What?
我们是去调查超能力者  不是去约会
This is a meta investigation; this is not date night.
我穿礼服很帅哦
I'm just saying, I look really good in a tux.
这是什么时候发生的
When did this happen?
你父亲消失的那晚
The night your father disappeared.
好吧  液氮
Well, well, well. Liquid nitrogen.
一种非常强力的助燃剂
That's a potent accelerant, is it not?
这地方本该炸到天上去了
Oh, this place it would have gone up. Whoa.
我父亲的成果全都没了
So, all my father's work is completely gone?
不一定
Well, not necessarily.
你想想
I mean, think about it.
警方把这场火灾定为意外
Police listed this fire as accidental,
但他们不知道这事跟凯特琳父亲的关联
but they didn't know about the connection to Caitlin's father, so...
拉尔夫  我父亲让我来找他
Ralph, my father told me to come find him.
我知道  但是你能相信一个
Yeah, no, I know that, but a guy who disappears
在仓库大火夜晚消失且再找不到的人吗
on the night of a warehouse fire and who's hard to find?
如果你认为是纵火  那我这么跟你说
Well, if you think this was arson, let me tell you,
如果是她父亲干的
if her father did this, well, he would need a lot of help
他得需要很多人帮他掩盖痕迹
covering his tracks, right?
也许真有人帮他
Yeah. Maybe he got it.
唐豪瑟
我妈妈也许不是圣人
Listen, my mom may not be the best person,
但她绝不可能参与这种事
but there's no way she'd be party to something like this.
只有问问才知道了
There's one way to find out.
你又想审问她的母亲
What, you want to question the mother again?
你已经做过了  得到了什么
You already did that, and what did you get?
什么也没有
Nothing.
这是条线索  我们得跟下去
Well it's a clue. Surely, we should follow it.
这里仍是唐豪瑟的地方
You already know that this is still
你搞错了
Tannhauser facility, okay? So you're wrong.
我错了吗
Oh, I'm wrong? I'm wrong?
是我弄清楚蝉的面具怎么回事
I'm the one who figured out Cicada's mask.
你根本搞不明白
You couldn't figure that out.
你说过不会质疑我  是你的错
You said you wouldn't doubt me, that was your mistake.
够了  够了  把这个给我
Enough, yeah, enough! Just give me this.
西斯科  西斯科
Cisco? Cisco?
-你看起来美极了  -谢谢
- You look amazing, by the way. - Thank you.
特丽萨·梅克尔在那  我们过去
There's Theresa Merkel. Come on.
你怎么跟她说
Wait. What are we going to say?
我们总不能直接问她  你儿子最近
We can't just ask her if her son was recently hit
是否被暗物质转化成了碎片
by dark matter into shrapnel.
-你想想怎么说  -我
- You'll think of something. - Me?
抱歉
So sorry.
梅克尔太太你好
Hi, Mrs. Merkel.
我是爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
I'm Iris West Allen.
我知道你
Oh, I know who you are.
你常常报道疯狂的罪犯
Don't you usually write about lunatics
还有抓捕他们的英雄们
and the heroes who catch them?
支持艺术也是全城关注的话题
Well, you know, supporting the arts is a citywide concern.
-是吗  -我是巴里·艾伦
- Hmm. - I'm Barry Allen.
很明显你们俩不是来慷慨捐赠的
And you're obviously not here to make a sizeable
也就是说亲爱的你们
donation which means you, my dear,
来这里是有任务的
are here on assignment.
随便问  你们有两分钟时间
All right, ask whatever you like. You have two minutes.
是关于你的儿子  彼得
Well, it's about your son, Peter.
你最后一次见到他是什么时候
When was the last time that you saw him?
那是两年前
That would be two years ago
当时他闯进了自己的家
when he broke into his own house.
我不在城里  我的员工报警抓了他
I was out of town, and my staff had him arrested.
你知道彼得现在在哪里吗
Do you know where Peter is now?
不知道  我也不在乎
No, and I don't care.
我给了他整个世界
See, I gave him the world.
最好的私立学校  只属于他的游戏区
The finest private schools, his own wing to play in.
但是他从不领情
But he just never appreciated it.
享受宴会吧
Enjoy the party.
我现在有点同情他了
I feel kinda bad for him now.
她真冷漠
She's so cold.
你能想象出这种生活吗
Can you imagine what that was like?
你知道吗  不跳支舞怎么能叫约会
Hey, you know what? It's not a date without a dance.
巴里  等等  我们在工作  对吗
Barry, wait. I mean, this is work, right?
线索中断了  我们还是回家吧
We just hit a dead end, so, why don't we just go home?
只跳一支舞  好吗
Just one dance, all right?
好吧
Okay.
我们从来没有过真正意义上的第一支舞
You know, we never really had our first dance.
是啊  这种感觉很好
Yeah, this is really nice.
等我一下
Excuse me for a second.
你还好吗
Hey. You okay?
她把所有的一切都给了她唯一的儿子
She gave her only son everything that she had
但还是不够
and it wasn't enough.
就像我给诺拉的还远远不够
Just like I'm not enough for Nora.
你和那个女人完全不一样
You are nothing like that woman in there.
你确定吗  巴里
You're sure, Barry?
我全心全意地爱我们的女儿
I mean, I love our daughter with all my heart,
但是她恨我
but she hates me.
因为我背叛了她
Because I turn my back on her
就像特丽萨·梅克尔对她儿子做的那样
just like Theresa Merkel did to her son.
关于她的一切我都欺骗了她
I lie to her about everything that she is.
我阻止她去过她应得的生活
And I prevent her from living the life that she deserves.
-我也会恨我自己的  -爱瑞丝
- I'd hate me too. - Iris.
你永远不会变成
You are never going to be the person
诺拉在未来认识的那个人
that Nora knows from the future.
这就是问题所在  这甚至不能由我们决定
That's the thing. It's not even up to us.
我已经变成她了
I've already become her
我甚至都没有选择
and I didn't even have a choice.
你还昏迷的时候  我扫描了你的伤口
While you were unconscious, I scanned your wounds.
依然有少量的铝铍合金
There are still trace amounts of aluminum-beryllium alloy
融在你的手掌中
fused within your hands.
那是蝉的匕首的残留物
It's remnants from Cicada's dagger.
听着  我只是需要休息
See, this is-- this is what I need. I just need rest.
不  西斯科  休息不能解决问题  好吗
No, Cisco, rest is not going to fix this, okay?
你每次用震波或者缺口时
Every time you vibe or breach,
暗物质都会影响你的中枢神经系统
the dark matter is going to affect your central nervous system,
让你越来越痛苦
causing you more and more pain.
等等  你今天肯定都在痛苦之中
Wait-- which you must have been experiencing all day today.
你为什么不说呢
Why didn't you say anything?
因为你是我的朋友  你需要我的帮助
Because you're my friend and you needed my help.
但是我永远不会要求你去伤害自己
Okay, but I would never ask you to hurt yourself.
你每一次用震波
Every time you vibe
都会引起越来越严重的癫痫
you are going to have more and more seizures.
那我应该怎么办
Then what am I supposed to do?
我记得这些超能力还是诅咒的时候
I remember when these powers were a curse.
看着斯旺一遍又一遍地杀死我
Seeing Thawne kill me over and over.
我知道那种黑暗
Knowing that darkness.
我不想那样
I didn't want that.
我不想做英雄
I didn't want to be a hero.
这些超能力是我的一部分  我得学会
These powers were a part of me. I had to learn that.
我做到之后  它们向我展现了一切
And when I did, they showed me everything.
我可以用震波感应一切
I could vibe every clue.
我可以把我们传送到任何需要的地方
I could breach us wherever we needed to go.
我可以为团队带来价值
I could bring my value to the team.
如果我不能承受痛苦  就意味着蝉赢了
If I can't take the pain, that means Cicada wins.
不
No. Hey.
听着  我明白  好吗
Listen, I get it, okay?
迪沃干掉冰霜杀手之后  我彻底崩溃了
When DeVoe took away Killer Frost, I was destroyed.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
我还在这里
I'm still here.
你也一样
And so are you.
因为你是西斯科·拉蒙
Because you are Cisco Ramon.
天才工程师
Genius engineer,
黑客奇才
prodigy hacker,
造出能拦截极速者的冷冻枪的机械师
and the mechanic who built a cold gun that could stop a speedster.
你还是我的朋友
And you're my friend.
你今天不断地在伤害自己
You're my friend who went out there and hurt himself today.
只为了帮我找到我爸爸
Just to help me try and find my dad.
这个人不是震波
And that wasn't Vibe.
是西斯科
That was Cisco,
这才是我需要的那个人
and that's the guy I need.
那把冷冻枪可相当棒
That cold gun was pretty amazing.
它当时差点被偷了
It was stolen almost immediately
对  当时
Oh, immediately.
但没错  它是很棒
But yeah, it was pretty great.
[追踪梅克尔无进展]
你知道  这个案子到早上还会存在
You know, this case will keep until morning.
是的  我知道  只是梅克尔还在逃
Yeah, I know, it's just Merkel's still out there.
而且那个舞会是死胡同
And the gala was a dead end
我们只知道他犯了两次完全不相关的罪行
and all we know is that he committed two completely unrelated crimes.
我不知道对诺拉该怎么办  巴里
I don't know what to do about Nora, Barry.
是啊
Yeah.
你知道我在这件事上站在你这边
Well, look. I mean, you know I'm on your side with this.
如果你未来抑制了她的超能力
If you dampen her powers in the future,
那是因为你关心她
it's because you care about her.
你是为了保证她的安全
You're doing it to keep her safe.
是的  仅仅因为我能保护她
Yeah. Just because I can protect her
并不意味着我是个好妈妈
doesn't mean that I'm a good mom.
这与弗朗辛的经历不一样
This isn't like what happened with Francine.
不一样吗
Isn't it?
她离开了我  我爸爸为了保护我而完全保密
She left me and my dad kept it a secret all to protect me.
然后她回来了  我把她推开
And when she came back, I pushed her away.
我几乎没有机会了解她  然后就...
I barely had a chance to know her before she--
我失去了和我妈妈交流的机会...
I lost my chance to connect with my mom and...
现在我变老了  诺拉也要推开我了
Now when I get older, Nora is going to push me away too.
那不会发生的
That's not gonna happen.
事情看起来正在朝这个方向发展
Well, it sure seems to be going in that direction.
那就选一条不同的路
Then choose a different route.
在你抚养诺拉的时候换一个选择
Make a different choice when you raise Nora.
如果你不想当那样的你  就不要当了
If you don't want to be that person, don't be that person.
没那么简单  巴里
It's not that simple, Barry.
你不是你妈妈
You're not your mom.
你不是未来的爱瑞丝
You're not Iris from the future,
而且你也永远不用成为她
and you don't have to be, ever.
我觉得你不要再担心
I think you should stop worrying
你会成为什么样的人了
about who you might become
而是重新定义现在的你是谁
and reconnect with who you are, now.
好的
Yeah.
我们回家吧  好吗
Now, let's go home, all right?
投资大亨举办慈善舞会
我能在那里和你碰面吗
Actually, can I just meet you there?
我觉得我有线索了
I think I have a lead.
好的
Okay.
不可能  爸爸居然唱了下去
Shut up. Dad did not keep singing.
你爸爸也绝不会
No way was your father
让初中的作品《红男绿女》
gonna let the middle school production of "Guys and Dolls"
变成一场灾难
turn out to be a disaster.
好吧  再讲一个
Okay, um, one more.
你爸爸十岁的时候
So, when your dad was about ten,
他的班上有一个小孩没了家人
there was a kid in his class that lost his folks.
小孩没有了笑容  也很少说话
Kid stopped smiling, barely spoke.
因为某种原因  学校里所有的其他孩子
And for some reason, all of the other kids in school
都对他很刻薄
were being so mean to him.
所以你爸爸和这个男孩一起吃午饭
So, your father had lunch with this boy
每一天都在一起
every single day
吃了一整年
for a whole year.
然后春天到了  年鉴出刊了
And when springtime came and the yearbook came out
你爸爸用一整页来展示这孩子
your father gave the kid an entire page
而他科学竞赛项目的照片
and the photos of his science fair project
让他获得"最具成功潜力"的称号
made him "Most likely to succeed."
然后这个男孩终于笑了
And then the boy finally smiled.
等等  但是爸爸并不在年鉴里面
Wait, but dad wasn't in yearbook.
这个故事不是关于爸爸的  是吗
That story wasn't about dad, was it?
是在讲妈妈帮助了爸爸
It was about mom helping dad.
等等  你讲的这些故事都是关于妈妈的吗
Wait, were all those stories you told me about mom?
诺拉  你总是在投射你30年后
Nora, you're projecting all of these feelings
对爱瑞丝的所有感觉
that you have about Iris 30 years from now.
你不会知道她今天是什么样子
You're not getting to know who she is today.
我告诉你的这些故事
These stories that I told you,
它们让我爱上了韦斯特一家
they're what made me fall in love with the Wests.
让我意识到这个家庭有多特别
Made me realize how special this family is.
所以...
So...
如果你爱他们  这里面还有更多
If you liked them, plenty more in here.
爱瑞丝
你好
Hey.
你好  宝贝  我刚和梅克尔女士谈了
Hey babe, I just spoke with Mrs. Merkel.
我觉得我知道彼得想要什么了
I think I know what Peter wants.
珠宝和大楼
The Jewelry, the building,
它们都是对受害者来说很私人的东西
they all meant something personal to the victim.
他想要造成
He wants to deliver
最痛苦的情感打击
the most painfully emotional blow possible.
就像他的家庭对他做的那样
Just like his family did to him.
你还好吗
You--you okay?
还好
Yeah.
对不起  这动机非常合理
Yeah, sorry, that MO fits perfectly.
你觉得谁会是他的下一个受害者
Who do you think's his next victim?
巴里
Barry?
过来找他
Come and get him.
各位  梅克尔绑架了巴里
Guys, Merkel kidnapped Barry.
-什么  -怎么可能
- What? - How's that even possible?
他偷了巴里的超能力者手铐
He's got Barry's meta-cuffs.
-难怪了  -你在给谁打电话
- Well, that would do it. - Who are you calling?
诺拉  快接电话啊
Damn it, Nora pick up.
我给巴里手机发指令  看能不能定位
I'll ping Barry's cell, see if I can get a location.
他在西蒙街的伊格尔沙姆公寓里
He's in Eaglesham apartments on Simone Ave.
他应该在公寓顶上  不是里面吧
I don't think he's in the apartments so much as on them.
没错
Right.
各位  我们现在没有极速者
Okay, guys. We don't have a speedster,
西斯科没法制造缺口  冰霜杀手又出不了场
Cisco can't breach, and Killer Frost is out of commission.
我们现在要想出办法救巴里
We need to come up with a plan to rescue Barry now.
外推器  我们可以伸进去抓住他
The extrapolator. We can reach in and grab him.
好  在哪里
Great, where is it?
好吧
Right.
关于这个...
Uh, about that...
被我弄坏了
I broke it.
你怎么弄坏的  击球训练吗
How did you break this? Batting practice?
-这东西不好用  -是你不好好用
- It's not user friendly. - You're not user friendly!
西斯科
Cisco.
我起码要一小时才能修好它
It's going to take me at least an hour to fix it.
-西斯科  我们等不起一小时  -我...
- Cisco, we don't have an hour. - Well, I--
不  但还有我在呢
No, but we do have me.
我们去救闪电侠吧
Let's go save The Flash.
哥们  真振奋人心啊
Oh, dude. That was inspiring.
-你有手铐钥匙吗  -多谢
You got a cuff key? - Thanks.
我来开车
I'll drive.
其实我想试个新招
Actually, I wanna try something.
我漫画书上看来的
Saw it in a comic book.
你勒死我了  勒死我了
Ah, you're choking me. You're choking me.
我以前住在这里
Hey, I used to live there.
拉尔夫
Ralph.
行  我稳住
Oh, I got it.
警察
Police man.
精心设计的手铐
Fancy cuffs.
彼得  这不是你想要的
Peter, you don't want to do this.
我知道你的超能力是怎么来的
Look, I know how you got your abilities.
是大悟之道那晚吧
The night of the enlightenment, right?
你被卫星碎片砸到了  对吧
You were hit by a piece of the satellite, weren't you?
压扁
Crushed!
折断
Snapped.
崩裂
Broken.
我认识能帮助你的人
Okay, well, I know people who can help you.
能帮助结束你痛苦的人
People who could stop your suffering.
痛苦不可能结束
Suffering can't be stopped.
尤其是她的
Especially hers.
你要是敢动爱瑞丝
If you touch Iris--
我不想听你的痛苦
Don't want to hear your pain.
只想听你妻子的
Only your wife's.
放了他
Let him go.
妻子来了
The wife.
你敢开枪  我就让他死
You fire, he dies.
好
Okay.
好的
别伤害他
Just don't hurt him.
凯特琳
来电
凯特琳  怎么了
Hey Caitlin, what's up?
听见她说的了吧  邋遢公子
You heard the lady, Raggedy Dandy.
放了他
Let him go.
好
Okay.
巴里
Barry!
妈  我的老天
Mom. Holy schrap.
你刚从房顶上跳下来救我爸
You just threw yourself off a building to save dad?
-对  -简直不能更酷炫了
- Yeah. - That was beyond schway.
-你疯了  -没错
- You're crazy. - I am.
-谢谢  我爱你  -我爱你
- Thank you. I love you. - I love you.
-天哪  -怎么
- Oh, my God. - What?
-拉尔夫还在上面
- Ralph is still up there.
千万别摔在我钥匙上
I hope I don't land on my keys!
你们还有超能力者手铐吗
You guys still have those meta-cuffs?
爱瑞斯·韦斯特·艾伦  彪悍的场面我见多了
Iris West Allen, I know badassery when I see it
你刚那一跳真是生猛  粗野  大胆
and that was raw, unrefined, cage-free,
纯天然的彪悍啊
non-GMO, badassery right there.
-你从房顶上跳了下去  -为了我
- You dove off a building. - For me.
差不多吧
Yeah, I guess I kinda did.
你当时在想什么
What was going through you mind?
"拜托  可别把钥匙弄掉了"
"Uh, please, God, don't let me drop this key."
你不害怕吗  你不是极速者
I mean, weren't you afraid? You're not a speedster.
我不是极速者
No, I'm not.
但我这位丈夫  搭档  最好的朋友是啊
But my husband and my partner and my best friend is.
我不是想打扰这个美好的时刻
Well, not to interrupt this wonderful moment
虽然已经打扰到了  不过
that I just interrupted, but, you know,
打败那个没骨头的笨蛋  我也有份
I helped defeat that boneless bozo too.
不简单啊  还有那...  那个面具
It wasn't so easy. And that--God, that mask.
就像瓷娃娃一样
It's like one of those porcelain dolls
晚上会杀了你的那种
that's gonna kill you while you sleep.
我觉得更像布偶人
I thought it was more like a ragdoll.
没错  取名还是我在行
Yeah, that's right. Still got it.
不用夸我
Hold your applause.
应该是要进铁山监狱的
Guess it's off to Iron Heights
老滑头布偶人吧
for slippery old ragdoll.
等下  你...  你要走了
Oh, wait, you're--you're leaving?
对  我有些事要做
Yeah, um, there's something I need to do,
但我会马上回来的  我保证
but I'll be right back. I promise.
她看起来很快乐
She looks happy.
对  她真的是
Yeah, she really does.
我也会做同样的事
I do that too.
我正在写你今晚做的事
I was writing about what you did tonight.
那真的很了不起
It was awesome.
谢谢
Thanks.
我猜那大概是我们家的特色吧
I guess it kinda runs in the family.
你从哪里拿到那个的
Where did you get that?
爸爸总是在把新的事记上去  真的很傻
Dad's always adding to it. It's so silly.
不  才不会  这是你的人生
No, it's not. It's your life.
我的意思是  你11岁成为校报的编辑
I mean, editor of the school paper by age 11.
15岁的时候曝光了学校老师的腐败行为
Exposing a corrupt school teacher at the age of 15.
你从来没有说过这些事
I mean, you never talk about this stuff.
我是说  在  在未来
In the--the future, I mean.
这是  你回避的话题之一
It's, um, one of your off-limits topics.
我不被允许去询问这些事
I'm not allowed to ask about it.
听着
Look.
诺拉
Nora.
我不是未来的那个人
I am not that person in the future.
而且在我这里没有什么不能问的  好吗
And nothing is off limits to me, okay?
我不会坐在书桌后面说''不''
I'm not gonna sit behind a desk and say "No."
我希望你好好过你的人生
I want you to live your life.
还有
And...
我希望你出现在我的人生中
I want you to be a part of mine.
没有秘密  没有隐瞒  就如
No secre, no lies, just...
今日的我们
Us being who we are today.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah, really.
你真的在三年级时监视学校洗手间
Did you really stake out the school bathroom in third grade
以证明清洁工没有打扫吗
to prove that the school janitor wasn't cleaning it?
我要杀了塞西尔
I'm gonna kill Cecile.
但  是的
But, um, yes.
我那时候是现实生活中的南茜·朱尔
I was a real-life Nancy Drew back then.
南希朱尔  是著名系列侦探游戏的主角  而且其中有些情节还被搬上银幕以同名电影而家喻户晓
妈  那真酷
Wow. That's cool, mum.
是吗
Um, is it?
秀兰和我聊了聊  发现我们的风格
Shirley and I were talking and while we realize our styles
大相径庭  但我们都喜欢的是...
are very different, what we both like...
一个好的谜题
Is a good mystery.
所以我们同心协力
So we put our heads together.
在想破了头后
And after some intellectual hair pulling,
我们发现如果你妈没有说谎
we realized that if your mom wasn't lying...
而唐豪瑟不知怎么的也牵涉其中
And Tannhauser was still somehow involved...
那不被他人发现的藏身之处
There's only one sure place somebody could hide
只有一个可能
without anyone knowing about it.
唐豪瑟的一个秘密行动点
A Tannhauser black ops site.
没错
There you go.
我是说  它们这种地方有很多
I mean, they've got dozens of them.
那些是疾病防治中心测试危险病原体的安全屋
They were safe houses to test dangerous pathogens for the CDC
但妈妈已经很多年没有为政府工作了
but Mom hasn't taken a government job in years.
它们应该都被关闭了
They'd all be shut down.
对  所以那是最好的藏身地
Yeah, that's why it's the best place to hide.
好吧  那我们怎么找到他们
Okay, so how do we find them?
在没有萨利的情况下  你试过谷歌了吗
Without Sally? Uh, have you tried Google?
对  我们就用它们的卫星吧
Yes. We just use their satellite.
我不认为我们可以用其他人的卫星
I don't think we can use someone else's satellite.
或者  我们可以
Or maybe we can.
当迪沃劫持萨利的同时  他自己也发射了
When DeVoe took over Sally, he also launched
四个人造卫星来引发大悟之道
four of his own satellites to bring about the enlightenment,
但现在他不在了  或许我们可以使用
but now that he's gone maybe we can work around the...
多路传输突破模型频道
Multiplexed burst-model channels
和交互SV切换
and the inter-SV handoff.
系统访问
我们有耳目了
We've got eyes and ears.
We've got eyes and ears!
我知道你做得到
I knew you could do it.
-抱歉  -犯傻了
- Oh, sorry. - That was dumb.
女士们和先生们  让我来向你们介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, may I introduce you to...
哈尔  罗比
HAL, Robbie,
戴塔和巨神兵
Data, and Colossus.
我不是很喜欢这些名字
I don't really like those names.
尽管如此
But nonetheless,
它们可以帮助我们追踪卫星的碎片
those can help us in tracking the shards from the satellite?
这些宝贝可以帮助满足我们的一切寻求
These babies can help with anything and everything.
一旦我们知道哪一个碎片击中了蝉
Well, once we figure out which one hit Cicada,
我们就能了解他是如何取得他的能力
we can figure out how he got his abilities,
也许就能找到他的弱点
maybe find some kind of a weakness.
那我们在等什么
So, what we are waiting for?
凯特琳  你知道这意味着什么吗
Caitlin? Do you know what this means?
我们可以定位到你父亲
We can locate your father.
等等  等等  我
Wait, wait. I, uh...
这难道不是你想要的吗
Isn't this what you wanted?
是的  我只是
It is, I just...
好吧
Okay.
等你准备好的时候
When you're ready.
谢谢
Thanks.